<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Simp1exp</title>
    <link>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Simp1exp</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>How this post is going to work? #  This post intends to bring a review of the course “Exploiting and Securing Vulnerabilities in Java Applications” available on Coursera, eventually, I also intend to bring some additional information. The dynamic of the post will be the same as the course, it’ll begin with an explanation about the topic, followed by a practical exercise trying to find the vulnerability, much like a CTF, and finally, explain how to fix it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/week-1/</guid>
      <description>XSS #  What’s this? #   Cross Site Scripting or XSS is a type of injection attack. All injection attacks consist in using the input field that the application provides to enter arbitrary data. In the XSS case, the arbitrary data is normally written in JavaScript, but may also include HTML, Flash, or any other type of code that the browser may execute. There are three types of XSS: Reflected, Stored, and DOM-Based.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2</title>
      <link>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/week-2/</guid>
      <description>Injection Attacks #  What’s this? #   Injection attacks are a class of attacks that consists of supplying untrusted input to a program. The objective is to get an exception case that triggers something, from there understand how this input is being sanitized, and then craft a payload. Between the vulnerabilities that fit in this category, SQLi (SQL Injections) and XXE (XML External Entity) are what we’re going to learn in this class  SQL Injection #  What’s this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3</title>
      <link>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/week-3/</guid>
      <description>Authentication and Authorization #  What’s this? #  These two are similar in the sense that they guarantee privacy, but they’re also different. Authentication is who you claim to be. Authorization is what you’re allowed to do.
In this course, authorization is only defined but not explored further to how these policies are ensured. So, some things like the access control model, vertical and horizontal escalation aren’t mentioned. Since my intention isn’t to go out of the scope of this course, I won’t talk about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4</title>
      <link>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simp1exp.github.io/posts/week-4/</guid>
      <description>Dangers of Vulnerable Components Introduction #  This week has much less content in comparison to the others. It focuses more on identifying flaws in your dependencies and updating them.
One tool used by the instructor is called dependency check by OWASP and it scans your project and returns a report with all the dependencies listed and categorizes one by one, saying if they’re vulnerable, if so, it also gives a link to a known CVE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
